hey guys this looks like a fun one it
says solve without logarithms this is
part two in part one I solved it with
logarithms this is what it looked like
right here a lot of people mentioned
there was an easier way to solve it the
reason I did it this way because I
wanted to show what it would look like
if the answer wasn't clean like x equals
6 if x had been some crazy irrational
number you'd have to go through all
these steps but since X was 6 there is a
way to do it without logarithms if you
want to try it on your own positive
right now cuz I'm going to solve it in 3
2 1 first want to express everything in
their prime factors so the N9 can be
broken down into 3^ SAR and the four can
be broken down into 2^ s and then to
break down the 144 let's make a factor
tree 144 breaks down into 12 * 12 and
then each 12 will break down into 6 * 2
so we have 6 * 2 * 6 * 2 and then each
of these sixes will break down into 3 *
2 so we have 3 * 2 * 2 * 3 * 2 * 2 in
this we have 3 * 3 which is 3^ 2 and we
have 2 * 2 * 2 * 2 which is 2 4
so 144 and its prime factors is 3^ 2 * 2
4 so we can change this 144 to 3^ 2 * 2
to 4th now we have everything broken
down into their prime factors we can
clean things up a little bit let's bring
this exponent out here and we can bring
this exponent out here and then this two
will distribute to both of these so this
would make it 2x - 10 and then down here
this two can distribute to both of those
so it'll be 2x - 16 and then next I
don't really like fractions so let's get
rid of this denominator we'll move this
over here and then we'll put in a one
placeholder and then we can focus on
this piece with the denominator using
these notes anytime you have 1/ n that's
the same thing as n^ the1 power so we
can rewrite this as this to the 1 power
and then next we can distribute this
negative 1 to both of these- 1 * POS 2x
is -2X and - 1 * -16 is pos6 and then we
can copy down the rest of it now we have
3 to some power * 2 to some power = 3 to
a power * 2 to a power let's make these
exponents for the 3es blue and we'll
make the exponents for the twos red if
this exponent were to equal this
exponent and this exponent were to equal
this exponent then this equation would
have to be true so let's solve for x for
both of these for this first equation
let's add 10 to both sides on the left
hand side we'll have 2X and on the right
hand side 2 + 10 is equal to 12 and then
to solve for x we can divide both sides
by two and we get X is equal to 6 and
then for this equation we can subtract
16 from both sides on the left hand side
we'll have -2X and on the right hand
side 4 - 16 is equal to -12 and then to
solve for x we can divide both sides by
-2 and that'll leave us with X is equal
to 6 so if x equal 6 this will equal
this and this will equal this which will
make the equation true that is the
answer to our question let's put a box
around it how exciting here's the next
problem I plan on working on if you guys
want to try it out I'll post the
solution as soon as I solve it how
exciting